Robert R. Humphrey Photograph Collection, 1949-1963 MS 431
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Robert R. Humphrey Photograph Collection 1949-1963
Collection number: MS 431
Humphrey, Robert R.
This collection is comprised of negatives and prints of vegetation types and landscape scenes taken by Robert R. Humphrey between 1949 and 1963. The collection also contains some reproduction photographs from “Views of the Monuments and Characteristic Scenes along the Boundary between the United States and Mexico. West of the Rio Grande. 1892-95”, published by the International Boundary Commission, United States and Mexico.
3 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None
Biographical Note
Robert Register Humphrey was born in 1904 in Palo Alto, Calif. He earned his bachelor's, master's and doctorate degrees in botany and geology from the University of Minnesota, graduating in 1933.
He worked as a range ecologist with the U.S. Forest Service for 15 years, then as a range conservationist with the U.S. Soil Conservation Service before working for the University.
Humphrey joined the UA faculty as an associate professor in botany in 1948. He was involved in ecology, range management and was published extensively. His most notable book was "The Boojum and Its Home."
He retired from the UA in 1966. After he retired, he and his wife traveled extensively in Mexico, Baja and California studying the boojum tree and ecology along the United States-Mexico border.
A professor emeritus of range ecology at the University of Arizona, Humphrey died March 13, 2002, at 97.
Organization
This Collection is arranged into 4 series.
Series 1: Arizona, 1949-1963
Series 2: New Mexico, 1956
Series 3: Other Locales, 1952-1961
Series 4: Miscellaneous, 1950-1962
The collection is comprised of negatives and prints of vegetation types and landscape scenes taken by Robert R. Humphrey between 1949 and 1963. The collection also includes some reproduction photographs from “Views of the Monuments and Characteristic Scenes along the Boundary between the United States and Mexico. West of the Rio Grande. 1892-95”, published by the International Boundary Commission, United States and Mexico.
The collection contains primarily photographs of grasses and other vegetation native to Arizona, New Mexico and Northern Mexico. It also includes photographs of boundary markers along the border between the United States and Mexico and some photographs of groups and individuals involved with Robert Humphrey in grasslands research. The negatives and photographs are housed in envelopes that are numbered, dated and include detailed descriptions of the contents. Several of the numbered envelopes are missing from the collection: numbers 9-28, 50, 254-255, 257, 387, 391, 629, 802, 928, 933-934, 961, 1081, 1022, 1046A, 1217 and 1283.
Each series is arranged alphabetically by county and then by locale within each county.
Everson, A. C.; University of Arizona. Agricultural Experiment Station; United States. Bureau of Land Management; University of Arizona. College of Agriculture; University of Arizona. Cooperative Extension Service; Botany—Southwest, New; Forage plants—Arizona; Grasses—Arizona; Grasslands; Phytogeography—Arizona; Phytogeography—Mexican-American Border Region; Plant ecology; Plant ecology—Mexican-American Border Region; Prairies; Range management—Arizona; Rangelands—Arizona; Vegetation boundaries—Arizona; Vegetation dynamics—Mexican-American Border Region; Mexican-American Border Region; Bulletin (University of Arizona. Agricultural Experiment Station)
- Series 1: Arizona, 1949-1963
  This series is arranged alphabetically by county and then locale within each county.
  - Apache County, Alpine Area, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Apache County, Ft. Apache Reservation, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Apache County, Navajo Reservation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Apache County, Rest of County, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cochise County, Babocamari Ranch, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cochise County, Blackwater Draw, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cochise County, Boundary Monuments, 1956; undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cochise County, Turkey Creek Ridge, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cochise County, Rest of County, 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Coconino County, Cameron, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Coconino County, Fredonia, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Coconino County, Grand Canyon, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Coconino County, Houserock Valley, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Coconino County, Kaibab, 1953; undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Coconino County, Kaibito, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Coconino County, Mogollon Rim, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Coconino County, Navajo Bridge, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Coconino County, No Location, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Coconino County, Rose Well, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Coconino County, San Francisco Mountains, 1953; 1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Coconino County, Seligman, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Coconino County, Rest of County, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Gila County, Joe Cosner Ranch, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Gila County, Pinal Mountains, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Gila County, Pioneer Pass, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gila County, Rest of County, 1953; 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Graham County, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Maricopa County, 1955; 1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Mojave County, Alamo Crossing, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Mojave County, Big Sandy, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Mojave County, Black Mountains, 1950; 1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Mojave County, Fredonia Area, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Mojave County, Hualpai Indian Reservation; New Water Tank, 1951-1952; 1962 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mojave County, Hualpai Mountains, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Mojave County, Kingman Area, 1950-1952; 1963 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mojave County, Mt. Trumbull, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mojave County, Peach Springs, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Mojave County, Pierce’s Ferry, 1950; 1952 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Mojave County, Tuweep Canyon, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Mojave County, Yucca, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Mojave County, Rest of County, 1950-1951; 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Navajo County, Navajo, Hopi, Ft. Apache Reservations, 1954; 1962 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Navajo County, Whiteriver Reservation, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Navajo County, Winslow Area, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Pima County, Arivaca, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pima County, Aros Ranch, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pima County, Avra Valley, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pima County, Boundary Monuments (1 of 2), 1892-1895 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pima County, Boundary Monuments (2 of 2), 1892-1895; 1958; 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pima County, Catalina Mountains, 1959; 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pima County, Desert Laboratory, 1949; 1952; 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pima County, Gardiner Canyon, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pima County, Hickiwan, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Pima County, Kaka, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pima County, Mexico Boundary, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pima County, Mt. View, 1953; 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pima County, Organ Pipe National Monument, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pima County, Papago Reservation, 1958; 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pima County, Quitobaquito Pond, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pima County, Reddington Pass, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pima County, Sabino Canyon, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Pima County, Sahuaro National Monument, 1952; 1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pima County, San Xavier Indian Reservation, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pima County, Santa Rita Experimental Range, 1949-1951; 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pima County, Sierrita Mountains, 1949; 1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Pima County, Thurber Ranch, 1954; 1958 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pima County, Tortolita Mountains, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Pima County, Tucson Mountains, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Pima County, University of Arizona Campus, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Pima County, Vaya-Chin, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Pima County, White House Bajada, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Pima County, Rest of County, 1951; 1953; 1958-1959; 1963 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Pinal County, Control Road, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Pinal County, Oracle Junction, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Pinal County, Page Ranch-Lehmann’s Lovegrass, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Pinal County, Page Ranch Burn #2, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Pinal County, Page Ranch 1952 Burns (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Pinal County, Page Ranch-Miscellaneous, 1950-1952; 1955 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Pinal County, Page Ranch-Plots, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Pinal County, Page Ranch-Runoff Area, 1951-1952; 1955 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Pinal County, Pinal Mountains-Russell Gulch Burn, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Pinal County, Pinal Mountains-South Slope, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Pinal County, Truck-mounted Spray Rig, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Pinal County, Rest of County, 1953; 1958 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Santa Cruz County, Arivaca (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Santa Cruz County, Atoscosa Peak, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Santa Cruz County, Boundary Monuments, 1892-1895; 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Santa Cruz County, Canelo Hills, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Santa Cruz County, Canelo Pass, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Santa Cruz County, Cumming Ranch, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Santa Cruz County, Josephine Canyon, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Santa Cruz County, Pajaritos Mountains, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Santa Cruz County, Santa Rita Mountains, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Santa Cruz County, Sycamore Canyon, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Santa Cruz County, Rest of County, 1954; 1956-1959; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Yavapai County, Aguila, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Yavapai County, Ashfork, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Yavapai County, Chino, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Yavapai County, Date Creek, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Yavapai County, Drake, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Yavapai County, Lonesome Valley, 1949; 1959 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Yavapai County, Octave, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Yavapai County, No Location, 1950; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Yavapai County, Perry Henderson Ranch, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Yavapai County, Perry Henderson Ranch, 1957; 1959 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Yavapai County, Skull Valley, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Yavapai County, Rest of County, 1949-1950; 1953; 1955; 1959; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Yuma County, Ehrenberg, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Yuma County, Gila Mountains, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Yuma County, Imperial Wildlife Refuge, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Yuma County, Papago Wells, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Yuma County, Rest of County, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Series 2: New Mexico, 1956
  - Dona Ana County, Boundary Monuments, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Hidalgo County, Boundary Monuments, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Hidalgo County, Near Boundary Monuments, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Luna County, Boundary Monuments, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Luna County, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Series 3: Other Locales, 1952-1961
  This series is arranged alphabetically by state (U.S.) and country then state.
  - California, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - North Dakota, 1952; 1961 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Mexico, Baja California, Laguna Chapala, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Mexico, Baja California, Mexicali, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Mexico, Baja California, San Filipe, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Mexico, Baja California, Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Mexico, Sonora, Puerto Libertad, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Mexico, Sonora, Other, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Series 4: Miscellaneous, 1950-1962
  - Maps, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - People, 1950; 1952; 1954-1958; 1962 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Unlabelled (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Empty envelopes (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Inventory of Photographs (Box 3, Folder 46)